# Wesley A. Beckner

CONTACT Information Benson Hall Room B17 Dept. of Chemical Engineering Cell: (817) 676-6617 E-mail: wab665@uw.edu Website: http://www.wesleybeckner.github.io

University of Washington Seattle, WA 1750 USA

RESEARCH INTERESTS Analysis and simulation of materials for energy and medicine using data science and statistical methods

EDUCATION

## University of Washington, Seattle, Washington USA

Ph.D. Student, Chemical Engineering, December 2019 (expected graduation date)

• Advisor: Jim Pfaendtner

## University of Texas, Austin, Texas USA

B.S., Chemical Engineering, May, 2014

### Honors and Awards

Data Intensive Research Enabling Clean Technologies (DIRECT) graduate trainee, 2016-2018 National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship Honorable Mention, 2015

Chemical Engineering Endowment, 2014

Achievement Rewards for College Scientists Fellow, 2014-2016

Friends of Alec Scholar, 2014

Undergraduate Research Fellowship, 2013

Tracor/Frank W. McBee, Jr. Scholarship, 2013

Texas Academy of Mathematics and Science Honors Diploma, 2010

### ACADEMIC Experience

## University of Washington, Seattle, Washington USA

 $Graduate\ Student$ 

September, 2014 - present

Includes current Ph.D. research, Ph.D. and Masters level coursework and research/consulting projects.

Study Abroad Teaching Assistant and Visiting Researcher

June - July, 2016

Co-taught unit operations labs for undergraduates from University of Wisconsin and University of Washington at Zhejiang University in Hangzhou, China. Emphasis on responsibility for professional writing and heat/mass transfer workshops. Assisted in the training of new graduate students to use molecular simulation engines in the research lab of Dr. Yi He.

Instructor

July - August, 2015

Co-taught programming course for data science incubator for social good at the UW eScience Institute. Shared responsibility for lectures, workshops, and homework assignments.

Teaching Assistant

January, 2015 - present

Duties at various times have included office hours and leading weekly computer and unit operations labs and exercises.

**PUBLICATIONS** 

W. A. Beckner, Y. He, J. Pfaendtner, "Chain Flexibility in Self-Assembled Monolayers Affects Protein Adsorption and Surface Hydration, a Molecular Dynamics Study", J. Phys. Chem. B.,

2016, 120(40), 10423-10432. DOI: 10.1021/acs.jpcb.6b05882

# Papers in Preparation

L. Schmser, M. Trefz, S. Roeters, W. A. Beckner, J. Pfaendtner, S. Woutersen, M. Bonn, D. Schneider, T. Weidner, "Refining the X-ray crystal structure of aquaporin with Sum Frequency Generation spectroscopy"

W. A. Beckner, J. Pfaendtner, "Application of Machine Learning and Molecular Simulation to Intelligently Design Solvents for Flow Batteries"

## Conference Presentations

Beckner, W. A., Application of High Performance Computing and Machine Learning to Accelerate Material Discovery for Energy Capture and Storage. American Institute of Chemical Engineers Conference, San Francisco, CA, 2016

Beckner, W. A., Green Events: Engaging Students in Sustainable Practice Through On-Campus Event Planning. Smart and Sustainable Campus Conference, Baltimore, MA, 2014.

Beckner, W. A., Entzminger, K., and Maynard, J. A. Site-Directed Incorporation of Nitrophenylalanine to Study Antibody:Nitro Group Interaction. Rice University Regional Undergraduate Symposium, Houston, TX, 2013.

## Professional Experience

## Campus Environmental Center, Austin, Texas USA

Assistant Director

August, 2012 - August, 2014

- Co-founded Green Events, a university-funded events consultation service for registered student organizations
- Provided network of campus resources to organization partners
- Executed and expanded campus sustainability initiatives
- Served as a student liaison between students and administrators
- $\bullet$  Planned milestone sustainability events including a world record-breaking build-a-thon on America Recycles Day 2013
- Participated in search committee with other administrators and facilities directors to hire campus zero waste coordinator

SKILLS

- Languages: C, Unix shell scripts, Python MPI parallel processing library.
- Applications: LaTeX, common Windows database, spreadsheet, and presentation software
- Algorithms: GROMACS molecular dynamics engine
- Operating Systems: Unix/Linux, Windows, iOS.